# Santiago Bustamante Garcia

+57 (300) 729 6896 busta117@gmail.com skype: sbusta117 www.santiagobustamante.info

## **SUMMARY**

I'm an engineer who love the new technologies with several years of experience developing native iOS games and applications both in academic and professional projects. I have experience developing REST APIs for communicate the client and the server. I have participated in multiple projects which gave me great experience personally and professionally working both by myself and in a team.

## **EXPERIENCE**

## iOS Developer, Rokk3r Labs

Bogotá, Cundinamarca — oct 2014 - current

I'm a outsourced iOS developer, currently i'm working on 1 iOS app.

## iOS Developer, Periferia IT

Bogotá, Cundinamarca — apr 2014 - current

I'm a member and leader of the iOS developer team, currently i'm in charge of 3 iOS apps: weHive (<a href="https://appsto.re/i6BX8MQ">https://appsto.re/i6BX8MQ</a>), The Squawka Football App (<a href="https://appsto.re/i6B986K">https://appsto.re/i6B986K</a>) and a in-house app

## iOS Developer, KOGI Mobile

Medellín, Antioquia — jun 2013 - apr 2014

I was a member of the iOS developer team, in this job i was in charge of some apps and participated in the development of more than 6 apps

#### iOS Developer, GARA Entertainment

Medellín, Antioquia — dec 2011 - jun 2013

I developed several games using Objective-C and frameworks such as cocos2D, box2D and Unity. I developed native iOS apps and theirs backend in php and WCF. In this job I was in charge of the development of Oh My Nuts!

Game(<a href="https://itun.es/i6Fk25f">https://itun.es/i6Fk25f</a>), their free version (<a href="https://itun.es/i6F27C2">https://itun.es/i6F27C2</a>) and two other games that are not in the AppStore yet, GoBo(<a href="http://youtu.be/nGUnDZoJ\_NE">http://youtu.be/nGUnDZoJ\_NE</a>) and StreetRep (<a href="http://youtu.be/LWIAKDe26OM">http://youtu.be/LWIAKDe26OM</a>); also i developed the ipad version for a colombian retail named ÉXITO (<a href="https://itun.es/i6Fk3H9">https://itun.es/i6Fk3H9</a>)

## iOS Developer, Doctus LTDA

Medellín, Antioquia — jun 2011 - dec 2011

I developed some frameworks for use in house, also started the development of several iOS games.

## iOS Developer, Freelance

I developed some iOS native apps for external clients, some of these applications still alive in the AppStore with the following links:

<u>https://itun.es/i6FV2yH</u> (internet radio station, Medellin Hip Hop)
<u>https://itun.es/i6Fk3H3</u> (sushi restaurant in Medellin-Colombia,
Sushi Market)

https://itun.es/i6Fk25x (events list for ANDI)

social network using GPS called MNU, this app is not alive

### **TUAPP Contest 2013**

I participated in the University Apps Contest powered by Cursor in Santiago de Chile, in this contest we're finalists with an application that suggests another way of tourism using quests (http://www.seekit.info/).

## **EDUCATION**

EAFIT University (Medellin - Colombia)

System Engineering — 2007-2013

## **SKILLS**

- Objective-C and iOS development for iOS 4.3 and above
- Java.
- PHP.
- MySQL.
- Xcode.
- Memory management and debugging for iOS apps using instruments.
- Cocos2D, Box2D and Unity frameworks for mobile game developing.
- C#

- WCF for REST API
- Adobe products (photoshop, illustrator, flash, premiere)